<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Tour of the Old Town</string>
    <string name="google_maps_key">AIzaSyDUKvElsnOVLhAPyJ7ghX81m7lyeX2D800</string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps">Map</string>
    <string name="allow">Thanks for the permission!</string>
    <string name="deny">Please allow the permission to enable the notificationservice!</string>
    <string name="lang">Language</string>
    <string name="options">Options</string>
    <string name="shutdown">Exit</string>
    <string name="notification">Notification</string>
    <string name="restart">Please restart the application!</string>
    <string name="historyText">
        Right from its early beginnings, the River Inn has determined the fate
        and growth of this border town which sits between Bavaria and Austria.
        It was first mentioned in a Passau charter in the year 804 as an agricultural
        settlement known as “Scardinga”. Shipping and commerce - first
        trading in salt, then grain, wine, ores, glass, cattle, wood and textiles
        - made the Schärding of the Middle Ages into a prosperous town. Following
        on from the Dukes of Vornbach and Andechs and the Babenbergers,
        the fortified border town was ruled alternately by the Wittelsbach
        and Habsburg dynasties. Schärding had become a football – or rather a
        bone of contention - that was kicked between the two neighboring lands,
        originally handed-down, then pawned, bartered and fought over.
        For around 500 years, Schärding belonged to Bavaria. In the 15th century,
        Louis VII “the Bearded”, Duke of Bavaria- Ingolstadt, fortified the
        town with moats, towers and gates. It was during the Middle Ages that
        the town grew and enjoyed its economic heyday. Sheep were farmed
        intensively all around the town and flax and hemp were cultivated, all
        of which led to the textile trade – with its linen weavers and loden wool
        workers, tanners and dyers – becoming the economic engine of the
        town. The cloth shears in the town’s coat-of-arms bear witness to this.
        The integration of the town into the flourishing agricultural economy of
        the Rott Valley also brought economic benefits.
        However, the upswing was interrupted several times by wars and fires.
        In the Spanish War of Succession in 1703, Austrian and Danish troops
        destroyed 50 houses in the town, as well as the gothic parish church,
        during an occupation which lasted three days. In 1724, 30 houses in the
        center of the town and the castle were destroyed by a fire which took
        hold during a procession to celebrate the Feast of Corpus Christi.
        However, the greatest devastation took place in 1809, as Napoleonic
        troops plundered the town and laid it to waste. 158 houses, as well as
        churches, the town hall and the Bürgerspital hospital, were destroyed
        in the town center. This also meant that Schärding fell into economic
        decline, from which the town – despite the huge efforts made - never
        quite recovered.
        In 1945, in the last days of the Second World War, the town came under
        attack from American forces, firing from the Bavarian bank of the Inn
        and totally destroying several houses and damaging more than 100. In
        the meantime, there have been strenuous efforts to preserve the historic
        character of the town. In 1966, 50 houses in the ancient Altstadt were
        declared to be historic monuments, in order to maintain the old architectural
        fabric at the heart of the town. In the meantime, these efforts have
        since been rewarded with the admiration and appreciation by the town’s
        many visitors.
    </string>
    <string name="historyLabel">History of Schärding</string>
</resources>